Guide to the George Dudley Seymour Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
George Dudley Seymour papers
1684-1944
MS 442
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
57
(128 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence, writings, photographs, research files, printed material, and miscellanea of George Dudley Seymour, a lawyer, antiquarian, historian, author and city planner in New Haven, Connecticut. Seymour's personal papers and collected manuscripts document the history of the Seymour family, the patriot Nathan Hale, the city planning movement in New Haven, Connecticut, and local history, 1684-1944. General correspondence files contain the bulk of personal correspondence, with many figures from the fields of art, education, politics, and sculpture represented, including William Howard Taft, a close friend of Seymour's. Family genealogy files include extensive correspondence, papers, and photographs Seymour accumulated in the course of his research on The Seymour Family (1939). Seymour also collected information and manuscripts relating to Nathan Hale, the Connecticut hero.
Seymour, George Dudley, 1859-1945
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by George Dudley Seymour, in accordance with his will, in 1947.
Arrangement
Arranged in six series: I. General Correspondence, 1831-1944. II. Family Genealogy, 1725-1943. III. Nathan Hale, 1701-1943. IV. New Haven City Planning, 1835-1935. V. Topical Files, 1684-1943. VI. Scrapbooks, 1883-1944.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, writings, photographs, research files, printed material, and miscellanea of George Dudley Seymour, a lawyer, antiquarian, historian, author and city planner in New Haven, Connecticut. Seymour's personal papers and collected manuscripts document the history of the Seymour family, the patriot Nathan Hale, the city planning movement in New Haven, Connecticut, and local history, 1684-1948. General correspondence files contain the bulk of personal correspondence, with many figures from the fields of art, education, politics, and sculpture represented, including William Howard Taft, a close friend of Seymour's. Family genealogy files include extensive correspondence, papers, and photographs Seymour accumulated in the course of his research on The Seymour Family (1939). Seymour also collected information and manuscripts relating to Nathan Hale, the Connecticut hero. As a pioneer in New Haven's early city planning movement, Seymour amassed correspondence with such figures as Cass Gilbert and Frederick Law Olmsted, Jr., minutes of commission meetings, and clipping files which detail much of the city planning activity engaged in during the early 1900s. Topical files and scrapbooks document a wide range of literary and professional activities, including Seymour's writings on New Haven and Connecticut history, and his legal practice in patent law.
The George Dudley Seymour papers total 57 linear feet and are arranged in 128 boxes. The papers are arranged in the following six series: I. GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE, 1831-1944, II. FAMILY GENEALOGY, 1709-1943, III. NATHAN HALE, 1701-1948, IV. NEW HAVEN CITY PLANNING, 1835-1935, V. TOPICAL FILES, 1684-1945, and VI. SCRAPBOOKS, 1883-1944.
Series I, GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE, contains the bulk of Seymour's personal correspondence, including both incoming letters and carbon copies of outgoing correspondence. Seymour corresponded with many important figures from the worlds of architecture, art, education, history, politics, and sculpture. Letters with several family members are also arranged here.
Among the important correspondents included in this series are: James R. Angell, Paul Wayland Bartlett, Cass Gilbert, Henry Solon Graves, Arthur Twining Hadley, Gifford Pinchot, James Gamble Rogers, Charles Seymour, Anson Phelps Stokes, Horace Dutton Taft, and William Howard Taft.
Series II, FAMILY GENEALOGY, contains the correspondence, photographs, miscellanea, and other papers Seymour compiled in the course of his search for information on the genealogy and history of his family. Detailed information on the individuals and family branches outlined in this series can be found in Seymour's published volume, The Seymour Family (1939).
In addition to Seymour's own correspondence, writings, and materials, this series includes the letters and documents of several early family members. Seymour "inherited" some items from other family members, including Seymour Morris, Nathan Perkins Seymour, and Mary Kingsbury Talcott. Other letters, deeds, documents, and photographs were acquired as Seymour expanded his research. Material for the Seymour, Churchill, and Welles family lines is quite detailed.
Series III, NATHAN HALE, contains the letters, writings, research materials, photographs, printed material, and clippings relating to Seymour's personal and professional interest in the American patriot, Nathan Hale. Letters with Hale family members, Hale scholars, and other individuals document Seymour's efforts to preserve and promote Hale's name. Files for numerous speeches, articles, and books are included in this section. Hale and Wyllys, and Documentary Life of Nathan Hale are Seymour's major works on Hale. Seymour's collection of manuscripts relating to Hale contains letters from Timothy Dwight, Eleazar Fitch, Richard Hale, James Hillhouse, and William Hull. (Seymour's collection of Hale manuscripts was donated separately to Yale in 1942 and is presently housed in the Beinecke Library.)
Seymour also obtained the papers of Victor Paltsits, a contemporary Hale expert, and manuscripts and photocopies of the letters and papers of Cyrus Parker Bradley and Jasper Gilbert, two nineteenth century Hale biographers.
As owner of Nathan Hale's birthplace Seymour compiled extensive files on the design, furnishings, and maintenance of the homestead. Seymour also participated in several celebrations, tributes, memorials, and monuments to Hale, including the placing of a Hale statue on the Old Campus of Yale University. Seymour also lobbied for the issue of a federal postage stamp honoring Hale. Many clippings and printed materials relating to Nathan Hale are also arranged this series.
Series IV, NEW HAVEN CITY PLANNING, contains correspondence, photographs, printed material, architectural drawings, clippings, and miscellanea from Seymour's work in urban planning. Correspondence with Cass Gilbert, Frederick Law Olmsted, Jr., Anson Phelps Stokes, and Lewis S. Welch is arranged here, as are files for the City Beautiful Committee, City Plan Commission, National Conference on City Planning, and the New Haven Harbor Development Commission.
Letterbooks Scrapbooks on New Haven City Improvement, (1901), 1907-1935; New Haven City Improvement Committee, 1907-1912; and the New Haven Harbor Commission, 1913-1923, further document the course of New Haven's municipal development and Seymour's leading role in this movement.
Series V, TOPICAL FILES, contains correspondence, research notes, clippings, photographs, printed materials, and writings on a wide variety of subjects. Many of Seymour's shorter-length articles, essays, and writings are arranged here. His interests in antiques, architecture, art, furniture, houses, and silver are also well-documented. Biographical files, containing partial bibliographies, and material from foreign and domestic travels provide an insight into Seymour's personal life. Correspondence with several clubs, societies, and organizations Seymour joined complements this material.
Other topics included in this section are: the law firm of Seymour, Earle, and Nichols; patent seals and certificates from the late 1800s; and such historical figures as David Austin, Daniel Burnap, William Burnham, Henry Caner, Amos Doolittle, Ralph Earle, and Ithiel Town.
Series VI, SCRAPBOOKS, contains thirty-five scrapbooks compiled by Seymour from 1883-1944. These scrapbooks contain clippings, printed material, photographs, correspondence, and miscellanea. Among the individual items arranged here are news stories and obituaries of friends and associates, and invitations, programs, and announcements for social occasions, university functions, and political forums.
One scrapbook, number 28, pertains to Seymour's 1902-1903 excursion to the Philippines with Gifford Pinchot. Volume twenty-six contains a series of clippings from the New Haven Daily Morning Journal and Courier (1883-1884), with thirty-two installments on the New Haven Elms and Green.
The George Dudley Seymour Papers were donated to Yale University on October 24, 1947, in accordance with Seymour's will. This donation, as enacted by the executor of the Seymour estate, culminated years of gifts and donations to the university by Seymour. His other manuscript donations to the university include the letters of Nathan Hale and a photograph album of William Howard Taft.
Biographical / Historical
George Dudley Seymour was born on October 6, 1859 in Bristol, Connecticut. He died on June 21, 1945 in New Haven, Connecticut. Seymour was a practicing patent attorney, antiquarian, historian, author, and city planner. Seymour wrote and published several articles and books. His primary areas of focus were the history of the Seymour family, the life of the patriot Nathan Hale, New Haven city planning, and many individuals and topics of interest in Connecticut history. His major works include: The Seymour Family (1939), Hale and Wyllys (1933), and Documentary Life of Nathan Hale (1942). Seymour also collected the letters of Nathan Hale. He purchased and restored the Hale birthplace in Coventry, Connecticut. Seymour also compiled a volume, New Haven, which consists of several essays he wrote on topics relating to Nathan Hale, Connecticut, and the city of New Haven.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Architecture; Art -- Collectors and collecting; Biography -- 19th century; City planning; Conservation of natural resources; Environmental protection; Forest conservation -- Citizen participation; Forest surveys; Genealogy; Harbors -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Libraries -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Monuments -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Parks -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Presidents -- United States -- Correspondence; Public buildings -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Public works -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Streets -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Connecticut -- Antiquities; Connecticut -- Description and travel; Connecticut -- History -- Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775; Connecticut -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783; Connecticut; New Haven (Conn.); New Haven (Conn.) -- Appropriations and expenditures; New Haven (Conn.) -- Description and travel; New Haven (Conn.) -- Economic conditions; New Haven (Conn.) -- History; New Haven (Conn.) -- Officials and employees; New Haven (Conn.) -- Politics and government; Philippines -- Description and travel; City planners; Historians; Lawyers; Abbott, Wilbur Cortez, 1869-1947; Allen, Frederic Winthrop; Angell, James Rowland, 1869-1949; Appleton, William S. (William Sumner), 1840-1903; Austin, David, 1759-1831; Bartlett, Paul Wayland, 1865-1925; Beaux, Cecilia, 1855-1942; Bingham, Hiram, 1875-1956; Burnap, Daniel, 1759-1838; Burnham, William, 1684-1750; Caner, Henry, 1700-1792; Chapman, John Jay, 1862-1933; Churchill, Charles, 1723-1802; Churchill, Charles, 1790-1845; Churchill, Mary; Cromie, George A.; Cutler, Manasseh, 1742-1823; Earle, Ralph, 1751-1801; Edwards, Jonathan, 1745-1801; Farnam, Henry W. (Henry Walcott), 1853-1933; Fisher, Samuel H. (Samuel Herbert), 1867-1957; Flint, Joseph Marshall, 1872-1944; Gibbs, William, b.1785-; Gilbert, Cass, 1859-1934; Graves, Henry Solon, 1871-1951; Hadley, Arthur Twining, 1856-1930; Hale, Nathan, 1755-1776; Hoadley, David; Hopson, William Fowler, 1849-1935; Huntington, Thomas, 1745-1835; Ingraham, Dudley S. (Dudley Seymour), 1890-1982; Ingraham, Edward, 1887-1972; Isham, Norman Morrison, 1864-1943; Jacobus, Donald Lines, 1887-1970; Jennings, Annie Burr, 1855-1939; Kimball, Fiske, 1888-1955; LaFarge, Louis Bancel, 1900-; Lawrie, Lee, 1877-1963; Lohmann, Carl A. (Carl Albert), 1887-; Meeks, Everett; Olmsted, Frederick Law, 1870-1957; Peck, Miles Lewis; Phelps, William Lyon, 1865-1943; Pinchot, Gifford, 1865-1946; Rogers, James Gamble, 1867-1947; Seymour, Charles, 1885-1963; Seymour, George Dudley, 1859-1945; Seymour, Thomas Hart, 1808-1868; Seymour, Thomas, 1668 or 9-1740; Seymour, Thomas, 1705-1767; Seymour, Thomas, 1735-1829; Seymour, Truman, 1824-1891; Shepard, James, 1838-1926; Shipman, Arthur Leffingwell, 1864-1937; Silliman, Benjamin, 1816-1885; Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1874-1958; Strickland, Emily M.; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930; Talcott, Mary Kingsbury, 1847-1917; Tinker, Chauncey Brewster, 1876-1963; Town, Ithiel, 1784-1844; Trumbull, Benjamin, 1735-1820; Van DeVanter, Willis, 1930-; Weir, John F. (John Ferguson), 1841-1926; Welch, Lewis Sheldon, 1867-1940; Welles, Edwin Stanley; Wilder, Amos Parker, 1862-; Churchill family; Hale family; Seymour family; Wells family; Yale University
- Correspondence, 1831-1944; Series I; 11.5; (35 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains correspondence arranged alphabetically by the individual correspondent.
  Letterbooks, dating from 1914-1919 and containing copies of outgoing correspondence, are arranged at the end of the series.
  Asterisks (*) indicate ten or more letters per folder.
  - Ab - Ad (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abbott, Wilbur Cortez(*), 1921-1942, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Acheson, Edward Campion(*), 1921-1927 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Acheson, Eleanor (Mrs. Edward C.), 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Adams, Charles Francis(*), 1831, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Adams, Frederick Baldwin(*), 1915-1943, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Adams, George Burton(*), 1896-1920 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Adams, Herbert(*), 1906-1943 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Adams, Adeline (Mrs. Herbert), 1916-1941, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ad - Al (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Alger, Philip R.(*), 1909-1913 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Allen, Frederic Winthrop(*), 1910-1933, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Allen, Irene (Catlin) (Mrs. F. W.), 1925-1943, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    General note
    See also: box 36, folder 326
  - Allen, William S.(*), 1916-1944, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Am - Ap (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Andrews, Charles McLean(*), 1914-1944, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Andrews, Evangeline (Walker) (Mrs. Charles M.), 1922-1943, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Angell, James Rowland(*), 1921-1943, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Angell, Marion (Mrs. James R.)(*), 1921-1930, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Appleton, William Sumner(*), 1912-1944, undated (Box 2, Folder 16-19)
  - Ar - Ban (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
  - Baker, Christine H. (Mrs. George P.)(*), 1928-1943, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Baldwin, Roger S., and Baldwin, [Olin?] P. (Mrs. Roger)(*), 1900-1944, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Bar - Bas (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Bartlett, Paul Wayland(*), 1906-1925 (Box 3, Folder 25-27)
  - Bat - Bea (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Beaux, Cecilia(*), 1894-1940 (Box 3, Folder 29-34)
  - Beaux, Cecilia(*), 1894-1940 (Box 4, Folder 29-34)
  - Bec - Bev (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Beers, Henry Augustin(*), 1898-1925, undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Bi - Boo (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Bigelow, Poultney(*), 1906-1942 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Bingham, Hiram(*), 1916-1933 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Bishop, William Henry(*), 1895-1927 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Blaney, Dwight(*), 1920-1934 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Blumer, George(*), 1909-1944 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Bor - Bre (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Brainard, Morgan B.(*), 1923-1944 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Brewer, Henry(*), 1906-1944 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Bri (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Bridgman, Donald S.(*), 1915-1944, undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Bridgman, Sarah, 1938-1944 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Bridgman, Walter Ray, 1910-1944, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Bridgman, Leoline W., 1914-1916, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Bro - Bru (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Brooker, Charles Frederick(*), 1911-1926 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Bu (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Cad - Car (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Carroll, John Haydock(*), 1927-1931 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Carroll, John Haydock(*), 1927-1931 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Cas - Chap (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Chandler, Joseph Everett(*), 1913-1917, undated (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Chapman, John Jay(*), 1918-1931, undated (Box 6, Folder 57-62)
  - Chas - Che (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Cheney, Howell(*), 1915-1931 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Chi - Chu (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Churchill, Mary(*), 1894-1927 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    See also: box 44, folder 550
  - Ci - Com (Box 7, Folder 67-68)
  - Comins, Eben F.(*), 1927-1936 (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Con - Cor (Box 7, Folder 70-71)
  - Cortissoz, Royal(*), 1925-1941 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Cos - Cox (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - Cr (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - Cram, Ralph Adams(*), 1906-1930 (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - Cromie, George A.(*), 1918-1943, undated (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - Crosby, Raymond Moreau(*), 1920-1938 (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Cross, John Walter(*), 1910-1944, undated (Box 8, Folder 78-79)
  - Cross, Wilbur Lucius(*), 1911-1941, undated (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Cu - Dan (Box 8, Folder 81-82)
  - Dana, Maria Trumbull(*), 1896-1943, undated (Box 8, Folder 83)
  - Dana, Richard Henry, Jr.(*), 1917-1935, undated (Box 8, Folder 84)
    See also: box 36, folder 341
  - Dar - Dee (Box 9, Folder 85)
  - Dean, Henry Charles(*), 1912-1915, undated (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - Deering, Frank C.(*), 1925-1936, undated (Box 9, Folder 87)
  - Deering, Joseph G.(*), 1918-1943, undated (Box 9, Folder 88)
  - Deg - Eb (Box 9, Folder 89-92)
  - Ed - Ev (Box 10, Folder 93)
  - Emery, Henry Crosby(*), 1901-1919 (Box 10, Folder 94)
  - Erving, Henry W.(*), 1913-1929 (Box 10, Folder 95-96)
  - Fab - Far (Box 10, Folder 97)
  - Farrand, Max(*), 1908-1941 (Box 10, Folder 98)
  - Farrand, Beatrix (Mrs. Max) (Box 10, Folder 98)
  - Fe - Fis (Box 10, Folder 99)
  - Fisher, Samuel Herbert(*), 1908-1944 (Box 10, Folder 100)
  - Fit - Fl (Box 11, Folder 101)
  - Flint, Joseph Marshall(*), 1916-1930, undated (Box 11, Folder 102)
  - Fo - Fre (Box 11, Folder 103)
  - Fox, George Levi(*), 1897-1928 (Box 11, Folder 104)
  - Fri - Goo (Box 11, Folder 105-108)
  - Gilbert, Cass(and family)(*), 1909-1937 (Box 11, Folder 109)
    See also: box 79, folder 1163-1166 See also: box 94, folder 1375
  - Goodhue, Bertram Grosvenor(*), 1908-1919, undated (Box 11, Folder 110)
  - Goodwin, William B.(*), 1909-1939 (Box 12, Folder 111-112)
  - Gor - Gra (Box 12, Folder 113)
  - Graves, Henry Solon(*), 1901-1944, undated (Box 12, Folder 114-118)
    See also: box 60, folder 828-830 See also: box 88, folder 1297
  - Gre - Gri (Box 13, Folder 119)
  - Griffith, Harold, and Griffith, Mary Elizabeth (Mrs. Harold)(*), 1937-1942 (Box 13, Folder 120)
    See also: box 60, folder 831-834
  - Gro - Gu (Box 13, Folder 121)
  - Gumbart, William Barnum(*), 1940-1943, undated (Box 13, Folder 122)
  - Hac - Had (Box 13, Folder 123)
  - Hadley, Arthur Twining (and Helen)(*), 1906-1927, undated (Box 13, Folder 124)
  - Hai - Haz (Box 13, Folder 125-128)
  - Hea - Hew (Box 14, Folder 129)
  - Hemingway, Louis Lee(*), 1925-1944 (Box 14, Folder 130)
  - Hig - Hop (Box 14, Folder 131-133)
  - Hopson, William F.(*), 1911-1934, undated (Box 14, Folder 134)
  - Hopson, Ada (Mrs. William F.), 1919-1937, undated (Box 14, Folder 134)
  - Hor - Hoy (Box 14, Folder 135)
  - Howells, William Dean(*), 1935 (Box 14, Folder 136)
  - Hub - Hy (Box 14, Folder 137)
  - Huntington, Maybel(*), 1934-1944 (Box 15, Folder 138)
  - Ib - Iv (Box 15, Folder 139)
  - Ingraham, A-S (Box 15, Folder 140)
  - Ingraham, Dudley S.(*), 1901-1944 (Box 15, Folder 141-144)
    See also: box 36, folder 365
  - Ingraham, Edward(*), 1898-1940 (Box 15, Folder 145-147)
    See also: box 36, folder 366
  - Ingraham, Edward(*), 1941-1944, undated (Box 16, Folder 148)
  - Ingraham, Faith(*), 1906-1942 (Box 16, Folder 149)
  - Ingraham, Grace Seymour(*), 1900-1921, undated (Box 16, Folder 150)
  - Ingraham, William and William II(*), 1907-1943, undated (Box 16, Folder 151)
    See also: box 36, folder 367
  - Isham, Norman Morrison(*), 1910-1942, undated (Box 16, Folder 152)
  - Ja - Je (Box 16, Folder 153)
  - Jacobus, Donald Lines(*), 1912-1944, undated (Box 16, Folder 154-155)
    See also: box 41, folder 496-498 See also: box 53, folder 696 See also: box 66, folder 933
  - Jenkins, Violet(*), 1913-1923, undated (Box 16, Folder 156)
  - Jennings, Annie Burr(*), 1916-1939, undated (Box 16, Folder 157)
  - Jennings, Annie Burr(*), 1923-1939, undated (Box 17, Folder 158-159)
  - Jo - Kel (Box 17, Folder 160-162)
  - Kelly, J. Frederick(*), 1915-1943, undated (Box 17, Folder 163)
  - Kelsey, Lillian D.(*), 1902-1944 (Box 17, Folder 164)
  - Kem - Kil (Box 17, Folder 165)
  - Kent, Henry W.(*), 1907-1944, undated (Box 17, Folder 166)
  - Keogh, Andrew(*), 1914-1938, undated (Box 17, Folder 167)
  - Kim - Kit (Box 18, Folder 168)
  - Kimball, Fiske(*), 1919-1937, undated (Box 18, Folder 169)
  - Kn - La (Box 18, Folder 170-171)
  - LaFarge, Bancel(*), 1919-1938 (Box 18, Folder 172)
  - LaFarge, John(*), 1899-1922, undated (Box 18, Folder 173)
  - LaFarge, Mabel (Mrs. Bancel)(*), 1916-1932, undated (Box 18, Folder 174)
  - LaFarge family(*), 1916-1932 (Box 18, Folder 175)
  - Lambe, William P.(*), 1904-1942 (Box 18, Folder 176-177)
  - Latimer, Robert C.(*), 1914-1944, undated (Box 18, Folder 178-179)
  - Lawrie, Lee(*), 1902-1944, undated (Box 19, Folder 180-182)
  - Le - Lin (Box 19, Folder 183)
  - Learned, Emily C. (Mrs. Henry B.)(*), 1908-1944, undated (Box 19, Folder 184)
  - Learned, Henry Barrett(*), 1906-1931, undated (Box 19, Folder 185)
  - Lindsay, Vachel(*), 1916-1922, undated (Box 19, Folder 186)
  - Lit - Lo (Box 19, Folder 187)
  - Lohmann, Carl(*), 1927-1942 (Box 19, Folder 188)
  - Lu - Ly (Box 19, Folder 189)
  - Luquiens, Huc-Mazelet(*), 1909-1941, undated (Box 19, Folder 190)
  - Mac - Men (Box 20, Folder 191-196)
  - Meeks, Everett(*), 1920-1941 (Box 20, Folder 197)
  - Mer - Mid (Box 20, Folder 198-199)
  - Mil- Munn, E. (Box 21, Folder 200-203)
  - Morse, Edward S.(*), 1899-1922 (Box 21, Folder 204)
  - Munger, Harriet R.(*), 1903 (Box 21, Folder 205)
  - Munger, Robert L., 1906-1938, undated (Box 21, Folder 205)
  - Munger, Rose M., 1907-1941, undated (Box 21, Folder 205)
  - Munn, Charles A.(*), 1917-1922, undated (Box 21, Folder 206)
  - Munn, L. - New Haven(*) (Box 21, Folder 207-209)
  - New York - Nic (Box 22, Folder 210-211)
  - Niemeyer, John Henry(*), 1898-1931, undated (Box 22, Folder 212-213)
  - Niemeyer, Anna T., 1924, undated (Box 22, Folder 212-213)
  - Niv - Pay (Box 22, Folder 214-219)
  - Parmelee, Vine R.(*), 1915-1940 (Box 23, Folder 220)
  - Parsons, Francis(*), 1897-1937, undated (Box 23, Folder 221)
  - Pea - Peck, J. (Box 23, Folder 222)
  - Peck, Hilda M.(*), 1898-1944, undated (Box 23, Folder 223)
  - Peck, M. - Peh(*) (Box 23, Folder 224)
  - Peck, Mary Seymour(*), 1906-1922, undated (Box 23, Folder 225)
  - Peck, Miles Lewis(*), 1896-1939, undated (Box 23, Folder 226-226A)
  - Pel - Pi (Box 23, Folder 227-228)
  - Phelps, William Lyon(*), 1897-1941, undated (Box 24, Folder 229)
  - Pinchot, Gifford(*), 1901-1944 (Box 24, Folder 230-233)
    See also: box 98, folder 1410 See also: box 116, folder 25
  - Pl - Po (Box 24, Folder 234)
  - Pomeroy, Margaret Winthrop Wylly(*), 1931-1943 (Box 24, Folder 235-236)
  - Pope, Theodate(*), 1906-1917 (Box 24, Folder 237)
  - Pra - Pri (Box 24, Folder 238)
  - Priest, Ann(*), 1937-1944, undated (Box 25, Folder 239)
  - Prihoda, Alois C.(*), 1940-1944 (Box 25, Folder 240)
  - Pro - Roc (Box 25, Folder 241-244)
  - Rockefeller, Percy(*), 1914-1933 (Box 25, Folder 245)
  - Rockefeller, Isabel (Mrs. Percy), 1912-1921 (Box 25, Folder 245)
  - Rog - Rol (Box 25, Folder 246)
  - Rogers, Francis(*), 1925-1940, undated (Box 25, Folder 247)